- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
Kids:
Aye, aye, Captain!
孩子们：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
Kids:
Aye, aye, Captain!
孩子们：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
Kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
kids: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
孩子们：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
All:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
[flute plays]
[长笛演奏]
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[upbeat bluegrass music]
[欢快的蓝草音乐]
♪ ♪
- Howdy, folks.
- 大家好。
Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐。
Why don't y'all
belly up to the beach
为什么你们不
腹部向上到海滩
and sit with me a spell?
和我坐在一起咒语吗？
I've got a Christmas
campfire story
我有一个圣诞节
篝火故事
I reckon you'll want to hear.
我想你会想听的。
This here tale
takes place underwater
这里的故事
发生在水下
in a one-seahorse town
called Bikini Bottom.
在一个只有海马的小镇
称为比基尼泳裤。
[festive music]
[节日音乐]
'Twas the day before Christmas,
那是圣诞节前一天，
and every boy and girl
was ready for Santa...
和每个男孩和女孩
已经为圣诞老人做好准备了……
- Hey!
- 嘿！
- Except one busy squirrel.
- 除了一只忙碌的松鼠。
She was using her science
to toil and tinker,
她正在运用她的科学
辛劳和修补，
but she found this experiment
a bit of a thinker.
但她发现这个实验
有点思想家。
- Aha!
- 啊哈！
A touch of tinsel
ought to do the trick.
一抹金属丝
应该可以解决问题。
Hey, elf Bob.
嘿，小精灵鲍勃。
- Oh, Sandy Claus.
[slurps]
- 哦，桑迪·克劳斯。
[啜饮]
I found the tinsel.
我找到了金属丝。
- Thanks for being
my little elf today.
- 谢谢你的存在
今天我的小精灵。
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[gasps]
[喘气]
both: Ooh.
两人：哦。
- What's this all for, anyway?
- 这一切到底是为了什么？
- This invention will
revolutionize Christmas.
- 本发明将
彻底改变圣诞节。
I'm fixing to reveal it
to the whole town tonight.
我正准备揭露它
今晚整个城镇。
It'll be my gift
to Bikini Bottom.
这将是我的礼物
到比基尼底部。
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
[defeated music]
[败乐]
[sighs]
- Congratulations, Sandy.
[叹气]
- 恭喜你，桑迪。
- Huh?
- You've done it again.
- 啊？
- 你又做到了。
- No, that ain't right.
- 不，那是不对的。
I gotta do better than that.
我必须做得更好。
I'll need a few more ingredients
我还需要一些配料
if I want this to be ready
in time.
如果我想让这个准备好
及时。
[high-pitched whistle]
[高亢的口哨声]
- What was that?
- 那是什么？
- Was that... no.
- 那是……不。
It can't be.
不可能。
- Slappy, did you
make that noise?
- 斯拉皮，你是吗？
发出那种声音？
- No, but I did make
a new friend.
- 不，但我确实做了
一个新朋友。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Ugh.
- Yeesh.
- 呃。
- 是的。
Both: Huh?
两人：啊？
- [grunts] Ta-da!
- [咕哝] 哒哒！
- Pa, Ma, Randy, Rowdy,
Rosy, Granny?
-爸爸，妈妈，兰迪，吵闹，
罗西，奶奶？
All: Howdy, Sandy.
全体：你好，桑迪。
- Howdy, y'all.
- 你们好。
- Why didn't you tell me
that you'd invited
- 你为什么不告诉我
你邀请的
your family to Bikini Bottom
for the holidays?
你的家人到比基尼泳裤
假期？
- 'Cause she didn't, SpongeBob.
- 因为她没有，海绵宝宝。
This here's a good old
Texas bushwhack visit.
这是一个很好的老
德克萨斯州丛林之旅。
[laughs]
[笑]
- We had to put a few holes
- 我们必须打几个洞
in the family row boat,
在家庭划艇上，
but it was worth it to see
our little aquatic acorn.
但值得一看
我们的小水生橡子。
- Yeah, sis, we came
all the way from Texas
- 是的，姐姐，我们来了
从德克萨斯州一路过来
just to spend Christmas with
little old smarty-tail you.
只是为了一起过圣诞节
小老聪明尾随你。
- And not at all because
Randy's on the lam again.
- 根本不是因为
兰迪又在逃了。
[siren wailing]
[警笛哀号]
- [yelping]
- [尖叫]
[horn honks]
[喇叭鸣响]
- Is the coast clear?
- 海岸畅通无阻吗？
- Well, shoot.
- 好吧，开枪吧。
If I'd have known
y'all were coming,
如果我知道的话
你们都来了，
I would have put the kettle on.
我会把水壶放上。
- [grunting] Help me, kids.
- [咕哝]帮帮我，孩子们。
- [giggles]
- Tag me out.
- [咯咯笑]
- 标记我出去。
- You need help, Auntie Sandy?
- 你需要帮助吗，桑迪阿姨？
- Make him turn blue.
- 让他变成蓝色。
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
[bell dings]
- Huh?
[铃声]
- 啊？
[foghorn blares]
[雾号声]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
What in the yellow snow
was that?
黄色的雪里有什么
是吗？
- [chuckles] Sorry.
That was my work alarm.
- [轻笑] 抱歉。
那是我的工作闹钟。
Yoop! Yoink!
哎哟！哟哟！
I got to get to the Krusty Krab
for my favorite shift
我得去 Krusty Krab
我最喜欢的轮班
of the whole year,
Christmas Eve.
全年中，
平安夜。
[bell jingling]
[铃声叮当响]
- Hey, why don't
we all tag along?
- 嘿，为什么不呢
我们都跟着一起吗？
- Oh, we'd just love to.
- 哦，我们很乐意。
We have dearly missed
all our deep-sea buddies.
我们深深地怀念
我们所有的深海伙伴。
[bluegrass music playing]
[蓝草音乐演奏]
[boinging]
[轰鸣声]
- Whoo! Merry Christmas,
Krusty customers.
- 呼！圣诞快乐，
克鲁斯提的顾客。
Aren't the holidays magical?
假期是不是很神奇？
- I think you mean tragical.
- 我认为你的意思是悲剧。
- Who upchucked in your eggnog?
- 谁在你的蛋酒里倒了酒？
[defeated music]
[败乐]
[coins jingling]
[金币叮当作响]
- Sing it again, Mr. Squidward.
- 再唱一遍，章鱼哥先生。
We need more Christmas tips.
我们需要更多圣诞节提示。
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
[clears throat]
[清嗓子]
♪ Krusty Krab, Krusty Krab ♪
♪ 蟹堡蟹，蟹堡蟹 ♪
♪ Eat here every day ♪
♪ 每天都在这里吃饭 ♪
♪ Something, something,
Krabby Patties ♪
♪ 某事，某事，
蟹肉饼♪
♪ Don't forget to pay ♪
♪ 别忘了付款 ♪
- Boo! Boo!
- You stink!
- 嘘！嘘！
- 你太臭了！
- Mr. Krabs,
why do I have to sing?
- 蟹老板先生，
为什么我必须唱歌？
I just play my clarinet instead?
我只是演奏单簧管？
- No can do.
- 没有办法。
I'm using it
as a yule log today.
我正在使用它
作为今天的圣诞日志。
- What?
- 什么？
[screams, groans]
[尖叫声、呻吟声]
[yelping]
[尖叫]
[clarinet playing off-key]
[单簧管走调]
[sighs]
[叹气]
[groans]
[呻吟]
- [laughs]
Howdy, Mr. Krabs.
- [笑]
你好，蟹老板。
You sure have a festive
Christmas caroler there.
你肯定有一个节日
那里有圣诞颂歌。
Bless his heart.
祝福他的心。
- Thank you, Mrs. Cheeks.
- 谢谢你，奇克斯夫人。
He could stand to bring in
a few more tips, though.
他可以忍受引进
不过，还有一些提示。
- Matter of fact,
I'm a little something
- 事实上，
我是个小东西
of a chanteuse myself.
我自己是一名女歌手。
Maybe we could strum up
some tips for you, huh?
也许我们可以弹奏
给你一些建议，嗯？
- As long as I don't have
to pay you.
- 只要我没有
付钱给你。
- SpongeBob, lights, please.
- 海绵宝宝，请亮灯。
[exciting music]
[激动人心的音乐]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- ♪ Well ♪
- ♪ 嗯 ♪
- ♪ Christmas is a time
for giving ♪
- ♪ 圣诞节是一个美好的时光
为了给予♪
♪ Christmas is a time
for getting ♪
♪ 圣诞节是一个美好的时光
为了得到♪
♪ Christmas is a time
for many things ♪
♪ 圣诞节是一个美好的时光
对于很多事情♪
♪ You know we love
trapeze flipping ♪
♪ 你知道我们爱
空中飞人翻转♪
♪ Climbing trees
and country living ♪
♪ 爬树
和乡村生活♪
♪ But nothing beats
the gifts that Santa brings ♪
♪ 但没有什么比
圣诞老人带来的礼物♪
- ♪ Yahoo ♪
- ♪ 雅虎 ♪
- ♪ Well, Christmas will come ♪
- ♪ 好吧，圣诞节即将到来 ♪
♪ And Christmas will go ♪
♪ 圣诞节即将过去 ♪
♪ But I can't deny
it's the day I love the most ♪
♪ 但我无法否认
这是我最喜欢的一天♪
♪ Everything's a-glowing ♪
♪ 一切都在发光 ♪
♪ When your stocking's
overflowing ♪
♪ 当你的袜子
满溢♪
♪ And Santa's gifts
are wrapped under the tree ♪
♪ 还有圣诞老人的礼物
被包裹在树下♪
- ♪ Yeah, Santa left
his gifts for you and me ♪
- ♪ 是的，圣诞老人离开了
他给你和我的礼物♪
[cheers and applause]
[欢呼和掌声]
- I'm dreaming
of a green Christmas.
- 我在做梦
的绿色圣诞节。
Whoo-hoo!
呼呼！
- And I'm dreaming
of a bah humbug.
- 我在做梦
一个呸骗子。
Good day, sir.
美好的一天，先生。
- Hmm.
- 唔。
Come on down
to my treedome tonight
下来吧
今晚到我的树顶
for a big Christmas surprise.
给你一个圣诞大惊喜。
[cheers and applause]
[欢呼和掌声]
- So, sis, what exactly
is this surprise
- 那么，姐姐，到底是什么
这就是惊喜吗
you keep going on about?
你继续说下去吗？
Or are you giving everybody
或者你给每个人
the old snake oil for Christmas?
圣诞节用老蛇油？
- [growls]
- Whoa! [grunts]
- [咆哮]
- 哇！ [咕哝]
- This ain't no scam, Randy.
- 这不是骗局，兰迪。
Now, hold your horses.
现在，牵住你的马。
I'm almost finished.
我快完成了。
I'll just add the extra
ingredients I collected today.
我只添加额外的
我今天收集的食材。
And voilà.
瞧。
- Ooh!
- Wow!
- 哦！
- 哇！
- Yee-haw!
- 哎呀！
It's finally ready...
and just in time.
终于准备好了...
而且恰逢其时。
All my friends
will be here tonight,
我所有的朋友
今晚将会在这里，
and I want to make this
Christmas special for them.
我想做这个
圣诞节对他们来说很特别。
- I reckon we can help you
impress the fins off this town.
- 我想我们可以帮助你
给这个小镇的鳍留下深刻的印象。
After all, special
is our specialty.
毕竟特别
是我们的专长。
Mm-hmm.
- You really mean it?
嗯嗯。
- 你真的是这个意思吗？
Thanks, y'all.
谢谢你们。
- We got a holiday stunt
spectacular to rehearse.
- 我们有一个假期特技
排练起来很壮观。
[laughter]
[笑声]
[festive music]
[节日音乐]
[indistinct chatter]
[模糊的喋喋不休]
- Merry Christmas, y'all.
- 圣诞快乐，大家。
- Merry Christmas, Sandy.
- 圣诞快乐，桑迪。
Say, did you gather us here
for some kind
说吧，你把我们聚集到这里了吗？
对于某种
of big Christmas surprise?
圣诞大惊喜？
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
As a matter of fact, I did.
事实上，我做到了。
- But whatever could it be,
some kind of...
- 但无论是什么，
某种...
breakthrough in holiday
decorative technology?
假期突破
装饰技术？
- Well, you'll just have
to see for yourselves.
- 好吧，你就会有
你自己看看吧。
- Hmm?
- Huh?
- 唔？
- 啊？
- I present to you
the instant Christmas tree.
- 我向你介绍
即时的圣诞树。
Just a few drops of this here
yuletide concoction, and...
这里只需滴几滴
圣诞混合物，还有……
whoa, a happy holiday
is all yours.
哇，节日快乐
都是你的。
[cheers and applause]
[欢呼和掌声]
And to help me celebrate,
my family will perform
为了帮助我庆祝，
我的家人将表演
their newest stunt spectacular,
他们最新的特技表演令人惊叹，
Dance of the Nutcrackers.
胡桃夹子之舞。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[magical music]
[魔幻音乐]
- Ooh.
[laughter]
- 哦。
[笑声]
[bluegrass version of
Tchaikovsky's "Russian Dance"]
[蓝草版本
柴可夫斯基《俄罗斯舞曲》]
[boinging]
[轰鸣声]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- Hup!
- 哈！
- Got you.
Hup. Yah!
- 明白了。
呵呵。啊！
- Ah!
- 啊！
[cannon booms]
[大炮隆隆]
Ah!
[laughs]
啊!
[笑]
[grunts]
[engine revving]
[咕哝]
[发动机转速]
[tires squealing]
- Ooh!
[轮胎吱吱声]
- 哦！
- [laughs]
- Oh!
- [笑]
- 哦！
Ah!
- Yeah!
啊!
- 是的！
- Here we go.
- 开始了。
Whoo-whoo!
Pew-pew-pew-pew-pew-pew-pew!
呼呼！
噗噗噗噗噗噗噗噗！
[magical music]
[魔幻音乐]
- Ho, ho...
- 嗬嗬……
[sighs] What a night.
[叹气]真是一个夜晚。
Good thing my 364-day
vacation starts tomorrow.
还好我的364天
明天开始放假。
Now, let's see.
现在，让我们看看。
Aha, Bikini Bottom.
啊哈，比基尼泳裤。
Saving the best for last.
把最好的留到最后。
See you back at the North Pole.
北极见。
And don't drink all my eggnog!
别把我的蛋酒都喝掉！
[alarm blares]
[警报声]
[festive music]
[节日音乐]
♪ ♪
Ho, ho, ho.
嗬，嗬，嗬。
A circus show?
马戏表演？
Now, that's
the Christmas spirit,
现在，那就是
圣诞气氛，
you party animals.
你们这些派对动物。
- Oh, Santa.
- 哦，圣诞老人。
- Hey, it's Santa.
Santa!
- 嘿，这是圣诞老人。
圣诞老人！
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Boy howdy,
that there's Santa Claus.
- 男孩你好，
那里有圣诞老人。
- I reckon we ought to make
our finale extra grand for him.
- 我认为我们应该做
我们的结局对他来说格外盛大。
[both chuckle]
[两人都笑了]
Ah.
啊。
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
- Ho, ho, ho.
- 嗬，嗬，嗬。
Merry Christmas, one and all.
圣诞快乐，一并。
- Now this will be
a Texas-sized tree.
- 现在这将是
一棵德克萨斯州大小的树。
- You know it.
[laughs]
- 你知道的。
[笑]
[rumbling]
- Huh?
[隆隆声]
- 啊？
Whoa!
哇！
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
- Whoa!
- 哇！
- Ooh!
- Wow!
- 哦！
- 哇！
- Ho, ho, ho.
- 嗬，嗬，嗬。
Huh?
啊？
Oh, Krampus.
哦，坎普斯。
Ow!
[screams]
噢！
[尖叫声]
[all gasp]
[全都喘气]
Whoa!
哇！
[grunting and shouting]
[咕哝和喊叫]
Ow!
噢！
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
哇哇哇！
Ow!
噢！
[all groaning]
[全都呻吟]
Whoa!
哇！
[squeaking]
[吱吱声]
♪ ♪
[groans]
[呻吟]
- [gasps]
- [whimpers]
- [喘气]
- [呜咽]
- Oh, my.
- 哦，天哪。
I hope he isn't too hurt.
我希望他没有太受伤。
[chuckles]
[笑声]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
Santa, talk to me, big fella.
圣诞老人，跟我说话吧，大家伙。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
Mrs. Claus, the Easter Bunny
is here to see you.
克劳斯夫人，复活节兔子
来见你了。
- Oh, that ain't good.
=> - 哦，那不好。
Come on, Santa.
来吧，圣诞老人。
Don't you know what day it is?
你不知道今天是什么日子吗？
- Of course.
- 当然。
Happy Valentine's Day!
情人节快乐！
Mwah.
[groans]
哇。
[呻吟]
- Oh.
- Oh, boy.
- 哦。
- 哦，男孩。
- That old elf is one sugarplum
shy of a fruitcake.
- 那个老精灵是一颗糖梅
害羞的水果蛋糕。
- Yeah, bro.
- 是的，兄弟。
How is Santa gonna deliver
our presents now?
圣诞老人要怎样送礼物
我们的礼物现在呢？
- He's not.
- 他不是。
Sandy knocked him
right out of the sky
桑迪撞倒了他
就在天上
with her big dumb tree.
和她那棵愚蠢的大树。
- That's exactly
why I don't trust trees.
- 正是如此
为什么我不相信树。
- But what's the point
of having Christmas
- 但这有什么意义
过圣诞节的时候
without any presents?
没有任何礼物？
- You, like,
totally ruined Christmas.
- 你喜欢，
完全毁了圣诞节。
[crying]
[哭泣]
[all grumbling]
[大家都在抱怨]
- Oh, no.
- 哦，不。
This is all my fault.
这都是我的错。
I'm so sorry, y'all.
我很抱歉，你们。
- It'll be OK, Sandy.
- 会没事的，桑迪。
At least Santa's
having a good time.
至少是圣诞老人的
玩得很开心。
- Hey, where are you going?
- 嘿，你要去哪里？
The party's just
getting started.
聚会只是
开始使用。
[party horn toots]
Whoa!
[派对号角声]
哇！
[party horn toots]
[派对号角声]
- Oh!
- 哦！
- And so the town
went quiet that night.
- 所以这个小镇
那天晚上很安静。
One by one,
they put out their lights.
一一，
他们熄灭了灯。
No fun to be had,
no joy to be doing,
没有乐趣可言，
做事没有乐趣，
just the soft, sad sounds
of gentle boo-hooing.
只是柔和、悲伤的声音
温柔的嘘声。
- [howls]
- [嚎叫]
[soft ukulele music playing]
[轻柔的尤克里里音乐演奏]
♪ ♪
- ♪ Oh, I should be
eating pumpkin pie ♪
- ♪ 哦，我应该是
吃南瓜派♪
♪ But instead
I made the whole town cry ♪
♪ 但相反
我让整个小镇都哭了♪
♪ What in the world
was I doing ♪
♪ 世界上有什么
我在做什么♪
♪ Now Christmas is ruined ♪
♪ 现在圣诞节被毁了 ♪
♪ I got the Christmas blues ♪
♪ 我感受到了圣诞忧郁 ♪
♪ I feel like
I just don't belong ♪
♪ 我感觉
我只是不属于♪
♪ Wish that I could sing
a happy song ♪
♪ 希望我能唱歌
一首快乐的歌♪
♪ Guess I'll just
sit here and stew ♪
♪ 我想我会
坐在这里炖菜♪
♪ And keep a-weeping boo-hoo ♪
♪ 继续哭泣 ♪
♪ I got the Christmas blues ♪
♪ 我感受到了圣诞忧郁 ♪
[bluesy harmonica music playing]
[蓝调口琴演奏]
♪
- Oh, if only
some unexpected fortune
- 哦，如果只是
一些意外的幸运
would just appear from above.
只会从上面出现。
- Hey, kin!
- 嘿，亲戚！
- Look what we found!
- 看看我们发现了什么！
- It's all Santa's gifts,
I tell you.
- 这都是圣诞老人的礼物，
我告诉你。
- Sure is.
- 当然是。
Can we keep them?
我们可以保留它们吗？
- Ooh, did you hear that, Sandy?
- 哦，你听到了吗，桑迪？
An unexpected fortune
just appeared from above.
意外的财富
刚刚从上面出现。
- Hold your seahorses,
SpongeBob.
- 握住你的海马，
海绵宝宝。
Ain't no use having gifts
if Santa can't deliver them.
有礼物没有用
如果圣诞老人无法送出它们。
- She's right, SpongeBob.
- 她是对的，海绵宝宝。
Santa's still indisposed.
圣诞老人还是不舒服。
- [barking like a seal]
- [像海豹一样吠叫]
- Meaning Christmas
is still ruined.
- 意味着圣诞节
仍然被毁了。
[chomps]
[咀嚼]
[high-pitched screeching]
[both groan]
[高亢的尖叫声]
[两人都呻吟]
- [clears throat]
- [清喉咙]
This ain't the first time
we had a year without Santa.
这不是第一次
我们度过了没有圣诞老人的一年。
I remember
the Great Elf Strike of 1874.
我记得
1874 年精灵大罢工。
Our whole town was real blue
that Christmas,
我们的整个城镇都是真正的蓝色
那个圣诞节，
but we made the most of it.
但我们充分利用了它。
No Santa, no problem.
没有圣诞老人，没问题。
We Cheeks banded together
and exchanged gifts
我们脸颊绑在一起
并交换了礼物
all on our own.
一切都靠我们自己。
The family Cheeks
ain't quitters.
脸颊家族
不是放弃者。
We weren't then,
and we ain't now.
那时我们还没有，
而我们现在不是。
- Granny's right.
- 奶奶是对的。
Let's do this for Santa.
让我们为圣诞老人做这件事吧。
[all cheering]
- ♪ Row, row, row your boat ♪
[大家欢呼]
- ♪ 划，划，划你的船 ♪
♪ Gently down the stream ♪
♪ 轻轻顺流而下 ♪
[bluegrass version of
Tchaikovsky's "Russian Dance"]
[蓝草版本
柴可夫斯基《俄罗斯舞曲》]
- Come on.
You can do it.
- 快点。
你可以做到的。
Uh-huh.
- [grunts]
嗯嗯。
- [咕哝]
- Giddyap, giddyap,
giddyap, giddyap.
- 吉德亚普，吉德亚普，
吉德亚普，吉德亚普。
[groans]
- [gasps]
[呻吟]
- [喘气]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- Huh?
- 啊？
♪ ♪
- Ooh, lookee.
- 哦，瞧。
[gibbering]
- [gasps] Oh, dear.
[胡言乱语]
- [喘气]哦，亲爱的。
- Whoa!
- 哇！
[jellyfish buzzing]
[水母嗡嗡声]
- [buzzing] Ho, ho, ho.
- [嗡嗡声] 嗬，嗬，嗬。
- [humming "Jingle Bells"]
- [哼着《铃儿响叮当》]
Huh?
[groans, screams]
啊？
[呻吟，尖叫]
- [gibbering]
- [胡言乱语]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
[birds tweeting]
[鸟鸣声]
- Ugh.
[laughs nervously]
- 呃。
[紧张地笑]
♪ ♪
- Looking good.
- 看起来不错。
- Whoo-hoo!
- 呼呼！
[foghorn blares]
[雾号声]
[laughter]
[笑声]
[engine turning over]
[发动机转动]
[horn honking "La Cucaracha']
[按喇叭“La Cucaracha”]
- Whoo!
- 呼！
- [gibbering]
- [胡言乱语]
Good luck delivering
those Easter eggs.
祝交付顺利
那些复活节彩蛋。
Mwah.
哇。
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
- Now, Sandy.
- 现在，桑迪。
Now, Randy.
现在，兰迪。
Now, Rowdy and Rosy.
现在，罗迪和罗西。
On Ma, on Pa, on Granny, and...
在妈妈身上，在爸爸身上，在奶奶身上，还有……
oh, me.
哦，我。
[laughs]
[笑]
[all laughing and cheering]
[大家欢笑和欢呼]
- I think we need
a little musical motivation
- 我认为我们需要
一点音乐动机
to get this job done.
完成这项工作。
- ♪ Well ♪
- ♪ 嗯 ♪
- ♪ Christmas is a time
for giving ♪
- ♪ 圣诞节是一个美好的时光
为了给予♪
♪ Christmas is a time
for getting ♪
♪ 圣诞节是一个美好的时光
为了得到♪
♪ Christmas is a time
for many things ♪
♪ 圣诞节是一个美好的时光
对于很多事情♪
- ♪ And you know
we like carol singing ♪
- ♪ 你知道
我们喜欢卡罗尔唱歌♪
♪ Skating round
and jellyfishing ♪
♪ 轮滑
还有捕水母♪
♪ But nothing beats
our nutty family ♪
♪ 但没有什么比
我们的疯狂家族♪
- [yodeling]
- [岳得尔调]
♪ Giving gifts means
I love you ♪
♪ 送礼物意味着
我爱你♪
♪ But not like spending time
so happily, hee-hee ♪
♪ 但不喜欢花时间
太幸福了，嘻嘻♪
- ♪ At Christmastime
both: ♪ At Christmastime ♪
- ♪ 圣诞节期间
两人：♪ 圣诞节期间 ♪
- ♪ Everything's fine
both: ♪ Everything's fine
- ♪ 一切都很好
两人：♪ 一切都很好
- ♪ 'Cause we got everything
we'll ever need ♪
- ♪ 因为我们拥有了一切
我们永远需要♪
both: ♪ We'll ever need ♪
两人：♪ 我们永远需要 ♪
- ♪ We may be miles apart ♪
- ♪ 我们可能相距数英里 ♪
♪ But you know in my heart ♪
♪ 但你心里知道 ♪
♪ This nut don't fall far
from the family tree ♪
♪ 这颗坚果不会掉得太远
从家谱上看♪
- ♪ Yee-haw
- ♪ 呀呀
♪ Places, y'all,
and here we go ♪
♪ 地方，你们，
我们开始吧♪
♪ Round and round
and turn to the right ♪
♪ 圆圆的
然后向右转♪
♪ It's Christmas Eve,
it should be bright ♪
♪ 今天是圣诞夜，
应该很亮吧♪
♪ The Krusty Krab
looks mighty low ♪
♪ 蟹堡王
看起来好低沉♪
♪ Come on, SpongeBob,
let's do-si-do ♪
♪ 来吧，海绵宝宝，
让我们做事做吧♪
- ♪ I'm so blue
- ♪ I feel the same ♪
- ♪ 我好蓝
- ♪ 我也有同感 ♪
- ♪ No Christmas gifts
- ♪ Dad, this is lame ♪
- ♪ 没有圣诞礼物
- ♪ 爸爸，这太蹩脚了 ♪
- ♪ Now, folks, don't worry,
and don't you fear ♪
- ♪ 现在，伙计们，别担心，
你不害怕吗♪
♪ Your Christmas gifts
will soon be here ♪
♪ 你的圣诞礼物
很快就到了♪
♪ But there is something
you must do ♪
♪ 但有件事
你必须这样做♪
♪ Or old Saint Nick
won't visit you ♪
♪ 或者老圣尼克
不会来看你♪
♪ Good crabs and whales
should be asleep ♪
♪ 好螃蟹和鲸鱼
应该睡着了♪
♪ No gifts
unless you're counting sheep ♪
♪ 没有礼物
除非你在数羊♪
♪ So bow to your partner,
go on ahead ♪
♪ 所以向你的伴侣鞠躬，
继续前进♪
♪ Knock yourself out
and go to bed ♪
♪ 打倒自己
然后去睡觉吧♪
[boinging]
[轰鸣声]
[bright bluegrass music]
[明亮的蓝草音乐]
♪ Now allemande left
and fly like a bluebird ♪
♪ 现在阿勒曼德离开了
像蓝鸟一样飞翔♪
♪ Randy and Granny
to the house of Squidward ♪
♪ 兰迪和奶奶
去章鱼哥的家♪
♪ Walk on your tiptoes,
give him his gift ♪
♪ 踮着脚尖走路，
给他礼物♪
♪ Don't wake him up, now,
better be swift ♪
♪ 现在别叫醒他，
最好快点♪
- ♪ But what's that noise,
holy mackerel ♪
- ♪ 但是那是什么声音，
圣鲭鱼♪
- ♪ Dagnabbit,
that sound ain't natural ♪
- ♪ 达格纳比特，
那声音不自然♪
[clarinet wailing]
[单簧管哀号]
♪ Sure ain't no silent night ♪
♪ 夜晚当然不寂静 ♪
♪ Squeaks and honks
and clarinet squawks ♪
♪ 吱吱声和喇叭声
和单簧管的嘎嘎声♪
♪ Stop that noise
with Christmas socks ♪
♪ 别再吵了
搭配圣诞袜♪
[muffled off-key notes playing]
[低沉的走调音符演奏]
♪ Now, Rowdy's next
and Rosie too ♪
♪ 现在，下一个是罗迪
还有罗西♪
♪ To Patrick Star's
we skip to my Lou ♪
♪ 前往帕特里克·斯塔 (Patrick Star)
我们跳到我的卢 ♪
♪ Now, sneak, sneak,
don't make a squeak ♪
♪ 现在，潜行，潜行，
别发出吱吱声♪
♪ That's a big old gift,
and it's starting to leak ♪
♪ 这是一份古老的大礼物，
开始漏水了♪
- ♪ It's sand, sand
both: ♪ Everywhere ♪
- ♪ 这是沙子，沙子
两者：♪ 无处不在 ♪
- ♪ Too late now,
better hop on a chair ♪
- ♪ 现在太晚了，
- ♪ This Christmas gift
is mighty quirky ♪
- ♪ 这个圣诞礼物
非常古怪♪
- ♪ That's OK,
I think Pat likes turkey ♪
- ♪ 没关系，
我觉得帕特喜欢火鸡 ♪
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
- ♪ Come on, kids,
you're doing fine ♪
- ♪ 来吧，孩子们，
你过得很好♪
♪ The next stop is ♪
♪ 下一站是 ♪
[gasps]
We're out of time.
[喘气]
我们没时间了。
We'll never finish delivering
我们永远不会完成交付
all these gifts
to Bikini Bottom.
所有这些礼物
到比基尼底部。
- Aunt Sandy?
- 桑迪阿姨？
- We brought along
that concoction you made.
- 我们带来了
你做的混合物。
Maybe it'll help.
也许会有帮助。
- Oh, it ain't gonna work.
- 哦，这是行不通的。
It's running short
on Christmas cheer.
所剩无几了
在圣诞节的欢呼声中。
- Well, we can fix that,
right, family?
- 好吧，我们可以解决这个问题，
对吧，家人？
- Yeah!
- ♪ Bum-bum-bum ♪
- 是的！
- ♪ 呜呜呜 ♪
- ♪ Christmas will come,
and Christmas will go ♪
- ♪ 圣诞节即将来临，
圣诞节即将过去♪
♪ What stays are the days
that we say I love you so ♪
♪ 留下的是日子
我们说我如此爱你♪
♪ Everything's a-glowing when
your stocking's overflowing ♪
♪ 一切都在发光
你的袜子已经满溢了♪
♪ And Santa's gifts
are wrapped under the tree ♪
♪ 还有圣诞老人的礼物
被包裹在树下♪
- I love you guys.
- Yes.
- 我爱你们。
- 是的。
- ♪ Gifts are so much better
when your family is together ♪
- ♪ 礼物好多了
当你和家人在一起的时候♪
- Ooh! Ho, ho, ho!
- 哦！嗬，嗬，嗬！
- ♪ Whether it's on land
or in the sea ♪
- ♪ 无论是在陆地上
或者在海里♪
♪ Oh, a holiday with you
is right for me ♪
♪ 哦，和你一起度假
适合我♪
- Yee-haw!
- 哎呀！
We made it just in time.
我们来得正是时候。
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
- Ooh, I have to tell Santa.
- 哦，我得告诉圣诞老人。
Santa!
圣诞老人！
- [yelps, gibbers]
- [尖叫声，胡言乱语]
What the... where am I?
这……我这是在哪儿？
- We saved Christmas.
- 我们拯救了圣诞节。
- Huh?
- 啊？
- Well, actually,
we ruined Christmas.
- 嗯，实际上，
我们毁了圣诞节。
But then we saved it.
但后来我们保存了它。
[squeaking]
[吱吱声]
- What happened?
- 发生了什么？
[peaceful music]
[平静的音乐]
Give me that.
- [laughs]
给我那个。
- [笑]
- The last thing I remember
was a big Christmas tree.
- 我记得的最后一件事
是一棵大圣诞树。
- Then you fell
on your rum-pum-pum-pum.
- 然后你就摔倒了
在你的朗姆酒上。
[laughs]
- We thought you was dead.
[笑]
- 我们以为你死了。
- [laughs nervously]
But you're fine now.
- [紧张地笑]
但你现在很好。
And we took care
of your Christmas presents.
我们照顾了
你的圣诞礼物。
- This means I'm off
the naughty list, right?
- 这意味着我要走了
淘气名单，对吧？
[crickets chirping]
[蟋蟀鸣叫]
- Oh, you fixed my sleigh.
- 哦，你修好了我的雪橇。
Oh, thank you, everyone.
噢，谢谢大家。
You all deserve
special presents from Santa.
你们都值得
来自圣诞老人的特别礼物。
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
How's this?
这怎么样？
- Appreciate it, Santa,
but I already got what I wanted
- 谢谢你，圣诞老人，
但我已经得到了我想要的
for Christmas this year.
今年圣诞节。
- We never needed nothing fancy.
- 我们从来不需要任何花哨的东西。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
Who needs presents, anyway?
到底谁需要礼物？
- Well, we're, like,
totally grateful for ours.
- 嗯，我们就像，
完全感谢我们的。
- How'd you know it was us?
- 你怎么知道是我们？
- Well, we found a little
squirrel fur on our gifts.
- 嗯，我们发现了一点
我们的礼物上有松鼠毛。
[blows sharply]
[猛烈地吹]
- You were also yodeling
on our rooftops all night.
- 你也唱过约德尔歌
整晚都在我们的屋顶上。
- But we all thank you
nonetheless.
- 但我们都谢谢你
尽管如此。
- No need to thank us.
- 不用感谢我们。
What's important
is that we're all together.
什么是重要的
就是我们都在一起。
- Uh-huh, but we also got
this big old tree.
- 嗯嗯，但我们也得到了
这棵大老树。
Sandy got it souped up for us.
桑迪为我们做好了准备。
- Figured y'all could
use it as a new house.
- 我想你们都可以
将其用作新房。
[excited chatter]
[兴奋的喋喋不休]
- Here we come!
- 我们来了！
- Now, that
is a Christmas present.
- 现在，那个
是一份圣诞礼物。
Seeing y'all was great,
but nothing beats free stuff.
见到你们真是太棒了
但没有什么比免费的东西更好的了。
[laughs]
[笑]
- Now, let's get
this Texas-sized tree
- 现在，让我们开始吧
这棵德克萨斯州大小的树
back where it belongs, Texas.
回到它所属的地方，德克萨斯州。
- Yee-haw!
[laughter]
- 哎呀！
[笑声]
Yee-haw!
呀呀！
All: Bye.
Merry Christmas.
全体：再见。
圣诞快乐。
- And that is the story of how
a family of nutty squirrels
- 这就是如何的故事
一群坚果松鼠
ruined and then saved Christmas
down in the deep blue sea.
毁了圣诞节又拯救了圣诞节
在深蓝色的大海里。
I know. I know.
I hardly believe it myself.
我知道。我知道。
我自己都很难相信。
All:
Merry Christmas, y'all.
全部：
圣诞快乐，大家。
- Whoo-hoo!
- [laughs]
- 呼呼！
- [笑]
- You all come back, now.
You hear?
- 你们都回来吧，现在。
你听到了吗？
[bell dings, seagulls squawking]
[钟声叮叮，海鸥嘎嘎叫]